# **SEAN GROGAN**

sean.grogan@polymtl.ca Polytechnique Montréal 514-207-0075 ◊ 802-448-0772

## **SUMMARY**

PhD Candidate in the Department of Mathematical and Industrial Engineering at Polytechnique Montréal. Has the ability and desire to teach courses in Operations Research and Management Science, Applied Mathematics, or using the tools for these fields like CPLEX, Gurobi, Python, C++. Teaching experience includes corporate training environments and one-on-one tutoring.

#### **EDUCATION**

## PhD, Industrial Engineering and Applied Mathematics (In Progress)

2016-Present

Polytechnique Montréal

Research Project: Optimizing flight operations of UAVs in search and rescue operations

## **MSc, Computer Science and Operations Research**

2016

Université de Montréal

Thesis: An adaptive neighborhood search algorithm for optimizing stochastic mining complexes

## BEng, Mining and Metallurgical Engineering Co-Op Program

2013

McGill University

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Journal Article: **Grogan, Sean**; Pellerin, Robert; Gamache, Michel (2021). Using tornado-related weather data to route unmanned aerial vehicles to locate damage and victims OR Spectrum.

Journal Article: Garnett, Holly Ann; **Grogan, Sean** (2021). I came, I saw, I voted: Distance to Polling Locations and Voter Turnout in Ontario, Canada. Canadian Journal of Political Science.

Conference Proceedings: **Grogan, Sean**; Gamache, Michel; & Pellerin, Robert (2019). Dynamically Routing UAVs in the Aftermath of a Severe Tornado. In Edition ProLog 2019. Metz, FR.

Conference Proceedings: **Grogan, Sean**; Gamache, Michel; & Pellerin, Robert (2018). The use of unmanned aerial vehicles and drones in search and rescue operations - a survey. In Edition ProLog 2018. Hull, UK.

Masters Thesis : **Grogan**, **Sean** (2016). An adaptive neighborhood search algorithm for optimizing stochastic mining complexes. Université de Montréal.

Editorial: **Grogan, Sean** (2013). Applying mathematical models to complex mining operations at Newmont McGill Reporter, Sept 19, 2013.

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# **English Language and Technical Writing Tutor**

2014-Present

Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

# **COSMO Mine Links Tutorial for COSMO Tech Day**

2015

Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

Sean Grogan 1 2021-11

## **COSMO Mine Links Tutorial for Newmont Mining Corporation**

Winnemucca, Nevada, United States of America

Lacrosse Coach 2011–2013

Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

National Officials Lacrosse Certification Program, Instructor

2012

2014

Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

#### AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

## **Polythechnique Scholarship**

September 2016

Polytechnique Montréal

Renewed Annually 2016 – 2021

## **Three Minute Thesis - Second Place**

March 2018

Polytechnique Montréal

3MT is a university wide competition in which participants present their research and its wider impact in 3 minutes or less to a panel of non-specialist judges.

#### EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

## English language proofreader, editor, and tutor

2014-Present

Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

Long range mine planner

2013

Newmont Mining Corp, Denver, Colorado, United States of America

Head coach

Dawson College Lacrosse Program, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

Short range mine planner

2011

2011-2013

Syncrude Canada Ltd, Fort McMurray, Alberta, Canada

## ACADEMIC SERVICE, VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE, AND OTHER CREDENTIALS

## Pro Bono Analytics, 10:12 Sports

June 2020 — December 2020

Baltimore, Maryland, United States of America

# PROLOG 2019 Project Logistic Scientific Committee and Track Coordinator

June 2019

IAE Metz School of Management, Université de Lorraine, Metz, France

#### First Aid and CPR Certified

**April 2018** 

Valid until March, 2021

Canada Heart and Stroke Foundation, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

## Loyola High School Science Fair Volunteer

Annually since 2014

Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

## **CONFERENCE PARTICIPATION**

## 2020 CPSA Annual Conference (Canceled, COVID-19)

June 2020

University of Western Ontario, London, Ontario, Canada

## 2020 CSDC Conference – Democracy and Diversity (Postponed, COVID-19)

April 2020

Centre for the Study of Democratic Citizenship, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

Sean Grogan 2 2021-11

PROLOG 2019 Project Management and Logistics

IAE Metz School of Management, Université de Lorraine, Metz, France

**Optimization Days 2019** 

May 2019

June 2019

HEC Montréal, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

**INFORMS Annual Meeting 2018** 

November 2018

Phoenix, Arizona, United States of America

PROLOG 2018 Project Managment and Logistics

June 2018

University of Hull, Hull, England

**Optimization Days 2018** 

May 2018

HEC Montréal, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

**COSMO Stochastic Mine Technical Days 2016** 

June 2016

McGill University, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

**COSMO Stochastic Mine Technical Days 2015** 

June 2015

McGill University, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

**CORS Annual Conference 2015** 

April 2015

Canadian Operational Research Society, Montréal, Quebéc, Canada

**Integrated Strategic Planning Seminar 2014** 

May 2014

Toronto, Ontario, Canada

#### SKILLS AND RESEARCH INTERESTS

Research Domains

Operations Research; Mathematical Modelling; Stochastic Optimization;

Metaheuristics; Hyper-heuristics; Mathematical Modelling with Uncertainty

Research Interests

Disaster Preparation; Humanitarian Logistics; Public Sector OR; Geographic

Information Systems; Natural Resource Utilization

Computer Programming; Mathematical Modeling; English Proofreading and

Editing; Computer Hardware Maintenance; Heavy Equipment Operation;

Machinist Experience

**Languages, Software** Python; C++/C; Java; QGIS; CPLEX; GUROBI

## GROUPS, AFFILIATIONS, AND SOCIETIES

Chaire de recherche Jarislowsky/SNC-Lavalin en gestion de projets internationaux

Institute for Operations Research and the Management Sciences (INFORMS)

Canadian Operational Research Society (CORS)

Centre interuniversitaire de recherche sur les réseaux d'entreprise, la logistique et le transport (CIRRELT)

Groupe d'études et de recherche en analyse de décisions (GERAD)

Groupe de recherche en gestion et mondialisation de la technologie (GMT)

Montreal Operations Research Student Chapter (MORSC)

Elections and Democracy Lab (LED)

## Formerly:

Skills

Stochastic Mine Planning Laboratory at McGill University (COSMO)

Project Management Institute (PMI) PMI - Montréal Canadian Political Science Association (CPSA)

# ON THE INTERNET

GitHub https://github.com/seangrogan/

GitHub (Research Material) https://github.com/seangrogan-researchprojects

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/seangrogan/ORCID https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1347-7874/

Google Scholar https://scholar.google.ca/citations?user=7J9ROKOAAAAJ

Web Site https://www.seangrogan.net/

Erdős number: 5